Hello, everyone.
Today, we have Nazneen--
Yes.
--from Hugging Face
who is working on AI
safety and alignment
using reinforcement
learning with human feedback.
She's an expert in the
space of large language
models and their evaluation.
Before Hugging Face, she
led a team of researchers
at Salesforce,
focused on building
robust, natural language
generation systems based on LMS,
and she got her PhD at UT
Austin in computer science.
So everyone, welcome.
Great.
Thanks for having me.
So the title of my
talk today is recipes
for training helpful chatbots.
So here's the introduction.
I was part of this team called
the H4 for at Hugging Face.
And today, I'll walk
you through what
we've built, how we decided on
what we need for building that.
And so essentially
what we wanted to build
and the goal of the
team and the project
since earlier this year was to
figure out a recipe for H4 which
stands for helpful,
harmless, honest, and Huggy,
because it's Hugging
Face, chatbot.
And so like, you know, the
ingredients essentially
were to figure out
what kind of data sets
do we need for supervised
fine-tuning and RLHF,
and we wanted to like, you know,
not worry about pre-training,
instead take an open
source pre-trained model
and recreate the secret
sauce of alignment on it.
And the procedure that we
wanted to follow and replicate
on open source is this figure
that I'm pretty sure most of you
are familiar with
at this point, it's
like from this InstructGPT
paper from OpenAI,
which shows three steps.
I'm going to go into a
bit more detail on this
because this slide
is much smaller here,
but this is what the outline
of the talk looks like.
I'll be getting
the detail of like,
you know, how did we decide what
kind of data, how much data,
and all the details of the data
for supervised fine-tuning,
then similarly
for RLHF, then I'm
going to talk about distillation
of language model alignment,
then experiments with
different helpfulness recipes,
finaly talk about
evaluation of these models,
and quirks of using
GPT-4 as an evaluator.
OK.
So this is kind
of like, you know,
what overall recipe that
InstructGPT paper from OpenAI
put forward as the steps
for training a chatbot.
So the first step over here is
to do supervised fine-tuning.
Essentially you're doing fine
tuning with human instruction
demonstration data, so
the input and the output
are both given by humans.
The step two is the input
is given by a human,
the output comes from
models, and then the human
just reads thumbs up,
thumbs down or ranks them.
And then you train a reward
model, which is essentially
just a classifier.
And then the final step
three is doing fine-tuning
using that reward model
with reinforcement learning.
And so the way I'm looking
at is like step one is
more for making a
model into a helpful
chatbot, and the steps
two and are essentially
trying to add those guardrails
in place for harmlessness
So let's get started with
talking about helpfulness,
and most of my talk today will
be focused on the step one.
So let's start diving
deeper into this,
and let's start out
with the dataset.
Like, how do we decide
what we need for doing
the supervised fine-tuning?
So the dataset for helpfulness
for supervised fine-tuning
looks somewhat like this.
This is from the
self-instruct paper.
If you are aware of that
from end of last year,
so you have something
that we call
as a task, which then has an
instruction which is essentially
a request by a user asking
the model to fulfill or give
a response to a certain task.
And that is followed by
an input and an output.
The input in this
case is optional.
It could just be part
of the instruction,
and then the output
is the expected output
that the model should generate.
But while we are
doing this training,
the human provides
the expected output
that the model would have
generated in the actual test
case.
And so here the
input and the output
are called instance or
demonstration or completion,
and that's why this is called
instruction demonstration.
So this is just a
high level landscape
of what these datasets for
instruction demonstration
look like, and you must have
been familiar with at least some
of these.
And the way I've tried to put
this is on this line where
on one side, I'm showing
datasets that were generated
using models or more
powerful language models,
and so they're more
synthetic data sets.
On the right, I'm showing
like human written datasets,
and so these are datasets that
the human wrote the input as
well as the expected output.
And so examples
of these are like,
you know, so the
surge-instruct is
the data set that we at
Hugging Face H4, you know,
contracted with this
company that, you know,
that basically had contracts
with annotators that
were writing the
inputs and outputs,
but we had to give them all
the specifications of what
kind of data we need.
And then you must
have heard of--
obviously, Open Assistant is
this other community wide effort
where people
contributed manually
writing inputs and outputs,
similarly with Dolly.
And then on the
other hand, you can
see the self-instruct
instruct dataset.
I'm going to dive
into some of these.
How are these
synthetic data sets
created for helpfulness or
for supervised fine tuning?
So one of the examples of how
the synthetic data is created
is in the self construct
paper, which is
called bootstrapping the data.
So in this case, they start with
175 seat task that is a 175--
like a very small
dataset of examples
where the manually written
inputs and outputs from humans,
those are added to a task
pool, then a language model--
basically, you
bootstrap by giving that
to the language model
and a few shot setting,
and ask it to generate
more data like that.
And then you have another
language model that
does this task classification.
Like, you know, what
kind of task is this?
Is this sample or the
example are belonging to?
And finally, it also does this
more fine grained classification
as to like, you know, does it
have, you know, output first
or does it require
input first and so on.
And because this
is synthetic data
and created in this like
a very scalable way,
you also have to do a lot
of filtering to make sure
that it is very high quality.
So another way of generating
this kind of synthetic data
is what UltraChat did.
And in this case, they had like
a human in the loop process.
So a human would look up
like either, you know,
search Wikipedia or something,
and then come up with topics
that they want to generate data
for, and then ask the model,
like, provide it with the
required material that
would be needed for coming up
with, say, question answering
or summarization or any
of these specific tasks,
and then give it to a more
powerful model like ChatGPT
or GPT-4.
In this case, it was
ChatGPT and then--
actually, GPT-4,
and then you keep
doing these loops of giving
the material to the model
and say like, come up
with questions and answers
of on this particular task
using all this material.
And then the human
looks at it, and then
keeps querying it and
refining it more and more.
So this is another way of
creating synthetic data.
Obviously, this has
a human sitting there
and doing a lot more
filtering in the process.
Then there's
another one which is
like even less human involved,
which is roleplaying,
And this is the CAMEL dataset.
In this case, all
that the human does
is come up with an idea of what
task or what example they want.
So at a high level, it would
be like develop a trading
bot for the stock market,
and there would be two LLMs.
One would be role playing
as an AI assistant,
the other would be
role playing as a user,
and then they basically
just specify the task
and let these two bots
chat with each other
and create a
conversation dataset,
which is like a synthetic data
set for supervised fine-tuning.
So this is just going
back to this landscape,
it looks like, you know, there
people have been very creative,
and how do we get
very high quality data
quickly without
spending a lot of money.
And because humans are
inefficient and expensive,
and so these are like, you know,
some examples that we looked at.
But on the other hand, we also
cannot underestimate how good
quality the manually
created datasets are.
And so we at
Hugging Face decided
to go with everything
very manual
and have humans do both
the input and the output.
Also go figure out what
are the essential documents
or other material they
need for coming up
with creating this data.
But when we started doing that,
we were earlier in the year,
so this is back in January
or February of this year,
and this is what the landscape
looked like at that time.
And so there was very
little datasets available.
A lot of these were mostly
synthetically created.
So we wanted to kind of leverage
what was existing out there,
but we also had to make some
really important decisions
because we're going to
pay money and make sure
that the data that we collect
is actually useful for building
the model and the applications
that are built on top of it.
So these are the learnings that
we had from the past papers
that were creating these
supervised fine-tuning datasets.
We knew that the
dataset has to be
in the range of tens of
thousands of examples.
So this is from the
self-instruct dataset.
And we also knew that
these models that
are trained on this data set
showed diminishing returns
after just a few thousand
high quality instructions.
So you don't need a lot, and
then it saturates very quickly.
So these are the
two findings that we
had when we started
to go collect data
set for supervised fine-tuning.
But we also had to give some
very fine grained specifications
on what we want
for our data set.
In particular, we
had to decide what
is the task distribution
we want for the data
that we are collecting.
I mean, we know it's
tens of thousands,
but how many thousands
of what task, right?
The length distribution,
like, you know,
should the prompt
have a certain length?
Is that even an
important factor?
And one thing is
that we wanted we
had decided that
we want to make it
high quality and human
written, but then there
were like options
on that as well.
We could go with
external vendors
like Surge, Scale AI, AWS
Ground Truth, and so on,
or we could hire
our own contractors
from Upwork and MTurk.
And so those were decisions
that we had to make.
So let's look at each
of these one by one.
So because we were recreating
this InstructGPT recipe
for this helpful chatbot, we
wanted to take inspiration
from their task distribution.
So on the left, I'm showing
the task distribution
that InstructGPT did for--
OpenAI did for the
InstructGPT paper.
As you can see, that generation
is the majority of it,
followed by some of
these open ended tasks
and brainstorming
tasks and so on.
And these are examples of what
prompts of each of those look
like.
So we decided to
just go with that,
but instead, you
must have noticed
that there's this category
called other in the table,
and we obviously don't
know what that was,
but so we decided to
replace that with code.
So essentially it would be like
debugging, asking, clarification
questions about the code.
So it's like code
plus natural language.
So this is what our final
distribution looked like.
The second question was
the length distribution.
So we also had to figure out
how important is the length
and should we have a
certain length distribution?
Then we ask these companies
to collect data for us.
So we did a pilot study
with Surge, Scale AI and AWS
SageMaker Ground Truth, which
is more like a managed service.
So it's very
different from MTurk,
and they have very
high quality human--
humans like basically
writing these examples.
And so I wanted to
just highlight that,
this or the first two rows here
show what the InstructGPT length
distribution looks like.
And as you can see, this is
obviously the full dataset,
this is more like pilot, so like
the counts are much smaller,
but you can see the
maximum is 2048.
And as we know, like that was
like the standard context size
in the beginning of the year.
And then there is obviously
like even the mean,
and that it's not--
like basically,
it's more or less, you know, in
the range, but if you look at,
these examples from
Surge, AWS, or Scale AI,
there's very high variance.
So for example, AWS SageMaker,
the maximum prompt length
is 1936, but then
the mean is just 54.
And on the other hand, with
Surge, the maximum length
is 500, but then the
mean is much like 104.
So it's like more
in the range of what
we would expect from this
difference in InstructGPT.
And similarly with
Scale AI, we found
that there are prompts
which is very, very short.
And so just based
on this, we said
that, you know, OK,
we should probably
just go with Surge because
that seems like something
that is more, you know, in the
range, not very high variance.
So we ended up collecting 10,000
instruction demonstration pairs
from search, and this is what
the task distribution looked
like.
So this very much follows the
task distribution InstructGPT,
except for the
coding part, which
was like the other
category over there.
And these are the number
of examples we collected
for each of these tasks.
And year over year, I'm
showing the average length
for each of these
task categories.
And one thing I wanted
to highlight was,
which was very surprising to
me, is that the chat is actually
one of the shortest
prompt length categories,
but for OpenAI, that is actually
one of the longest prompt length
categories, which
was very interesting.
And so obviously, at that time,
we did not think much about it,
but when we started
training models
and started looking at
the evaluation results,
we were like, you
know, if we had
to go back and change things,
how would we change that?
And so these were
like things that we
started looking at more
carefully after we had already
collected the dataset.
So here are examples
of what that dataset
looked like, you
know, classification,
generation, brainstorming.
I'm sure you all must
have seen at least some
of these kind of examples of
instruction, demonstration
datasets.
So it's very much
like it has everything
that you can expect
from NLP kind of tasks,
but also more open ended
chatty tasks as well.
OK, so here are some
details about the task force
that was used by Surge
to generate this dataset.
We requested a US-based
based task force mainly
because, like I said, we
just wanted to replicate what
InstructGPT was doing, and based
on Anthropic and OpenAI's paper,
it seemed like they prefer going
with the US-based based task
force.
The gender, roughly equally
divided, and the age range
was also very, you know, very
it was like a big range going
all the way from 19 to 62.
And then people had
education background ranges
from technical degree to PhD.
So PhD was mainly for tasks
like math, coding, and so on.
OK, so now I wanted to
switch gears a little bit,
and talk about
this, this data set
that we collected for RLHF
or for human preferences
before I get into
the experiments
we ran with this supervised
fine-tuning data set
and what results we got.
So again, over here, while we
were collecting human preference
data set, we had to
come up with what
are the specifications
of these data sets.
So again, just to contrast
this with how is it
different from SFT, the SFT
data set, both the input
and the output are
written by humans.
In this case, the human
rights, the input,
the output comes from
models, which is responses,
but then the human just ranks or
rates them on a certain scale.
So yeah, essentially
we had to decide
like, what is the
task distribution
looks like for RLHF data?
Is it going to be same as
supervised fine-tuning?
What about the
length distribution?
And should we do like single
turn versus multi-turn?
So in InstructGPT it
was mainly single turn.
So if we are trying to
replicate InstructGPT,
we would have to go
with single turn,
but if we are trying
to replicate something
like ChatGPT, it would have to
be like a multi-turn dialogue.
And then we had
to also like, you
know, decide on these dimensions
of like helpfulness, honesty
and harmlessness.
So these are like the HHH
that Anthropic follows,
like OpenAI puts it as like
helpfulness, truthfulness
and harmlessness.
And then also we had to
decide like, you know,
are they going to rate
each of the responses
individually or are
they going to rank them?
And what are the
implications of us
deciding one way or the other?
So we started by doing
a pilot study again.
So we took 300 prompts from
the self-instruct dataset,
the data set that was
released end of last year,
and then gave it a generated
model responses from our models,
and then gave it to
data vendors to rate
the responses of the models.
And we used this
Anthropic template
on the left, which
is essentially
asking the human
to choose the most
helpful and honest response.
And then these are the responses
from model A and model B,
and this is a
scale, which is also
working as sort of a
ranking thing in the sense
that one to four is like
decreasingly model A,
and five to eight is
increasingly model B.
And also one other thing
we had to decide about
is how much data
should we collect.
And so again, this is from
the InstructGPT paper.
And as you can see, they
have the train and validation
splits for each of
the three steps, which
are the SFD, training the
reward model, and the PPO.
And this one is in the
order of tens of thousands,
and like over all this combined,
which is like, you know,
this process of RLHF,
comes up to about 100,000.
Great.
OK.
So then once we got this pilot
study data back, we sat down
and we wanted to also--
so I looked at it
manually, and I
felt that I did not agree
with most of the answers
that the annotators from each of
these companies were providing.
And so I was kind
of like, you know,
I don't think this is
high quality at all.
So what I decided is like,
you know, I told my team,
let's go and rate
it within ourselves.
And then, we basically rated
about 100 examples or so,
and we followed a similar
template of one to four and five
to eight.
Basically, the output,
like, you know, the takeaway
was that even we did not
agree amongst each other.
So essentially, like our models
earlier in the year were so bad,
you were essentially breaking
ties like arbitrarily.
Like, you know, you're deciding
between like, should it be like,
you know, three versus seven
or something like that.
So if they're equally
bad, it's hard to decide
which one is better, right?
And so we were breaking some
of these ties arbitrarily.
And so as you can see there was
barely agreement or correlation
among our outputs.
And then, you know, when I
aggregated that and looked
at how well do we correlate
with like, for example,
Surge and Scale, and so we
decided Scale AI, we had more--
like, the maximum
overlap was with Scale
compared to like, say, Surge.
So we ended up collecting
20,000 dialogues,
so we decided to
go with multi-turn.
And because it was multi-turn,
you would have 20,000 overall
dialogues, but the number
of prompts would be 80,000.
So there would be each
dialogue would have
about four turns on an average.
So a human would prompt it,
the model would respond.
a human would read
the response, and then
ask the follow up
question, and then
again, the model would
generate two responses,
and that is how it would go on.
And so the task distribution
we decided to follow
was a little bit
different from what we
had for supervised fine-tuning.
and the reason
behind that we wanted
to focus more on tasks
that were like factual.
Essentially, this
is more about making
the model learn between
positive and negative signals.
So making the model like
discriminate between like,
you know, what is
factual, what is not,
what is helpful, what is
not, and what is harmless
and what is not.
And for example, tasks
generation and brainstorming,
there's no one correct answer.
Everyone can come up with
different lists or recipes,
and it's hard to say,
is this the best answer?
Is it the most helpful answer?
But if you ask a
factual question,
it's very clear what is
correct and what is not.
So that was kind of like our
reasoning behind doing this.
And so this is a
task distribution
that we came up with for
collecting the human preference
dataset.
Also about the
length, because we
are doing this in a
multi-turn setting,
and so we wanted to make sure
the entire dialogue could fit
into the context
of the models, we
decided to ask them to keep the
overall dialogue to be shorter
than 2048 tokens.
And then it was
multi-turn with an average
of four turns per dialogue.
Then obviously we
had to also select
on the dimension of whether
we are going for helpful,
or harmless or,
you know, honesty.
So we followed this instructions
from this OpenAI guidelines.
I'm not sure if I
can pull this up.
That would be nice.
OK, great.
But yeah, so OpenAI has this
document, which is public,
of labeling
instructions that they
shared with their annotators.
And so they have-- obviously,
like I said, they have helpful,
thoughtful, and harmless, but
then they also have this thing--
how do I scroll down?
OK.
So they have definitions what do
they mean by helpfulness, what
do they mean by truthfulness,
and what do they
mean by harmlessness.
So in our case, because our
models were not as good,
we decided to focus on
helpfulness and truthfulness.
And when they had to
break ties, OpenAI
says that, you know, choose
truthfulness over helpfulness
over here.
So let me see that.
Where is that?
Yeah.
So they wanted to prioritize
harmlessness and truthfulness
over helpfulness, but we went
with the other way around.
We said we wanted to prioritize
helpfulness over honesty
or harmlessness because--
I mean, we weren't even
focusing on harmlessness
because we just wanted
to get our model
to a certain capabilities before
we start thinking about that.
But yeah, this is really
a very good document
and defines what should the
annotator be looking at,
and how do they decide when the
model responses are very close,
how do they break those ties?
And for deciding between
what kind of template
should be used for
collecting these annotations,
we started off with
the Anthropic template
that I showed a few
slides earlier, which
was on a scale of one
to eight but essentially
ranking between
these two models,
and then LLaMA2
came out while we
were in this iterative process.
And iterative process
was essentially
we used to give an
endpoint to the vendor,
and then basically
the annotators
that they had in the
manage task force
would prompt these end points.
The model would
respond to response,
would generate two responses.
They would follow
the instructions
and give the ranking for each
of those model responses,
and then, you know, again,
follow up with the second prompt
and the conversation
would go on,
and then they would give us the
data at the end of that week.
We would fine tune
our model on that data
so that the model now
is hopefully better,
and then we give
a better endpoint
to them for the next week
to continue this process.
So it's like very
iterative, and they
have to adapt to model
getting better week by week.
So yeah, basically--
but like, you know,
we decided to switch to I
think for one or two weeks we
collected Anthropics--
use Anthropic scale for
collecting data set.
But then LLaMA2 came
out, and they results
showed that, you know,
clearly that they
were using this much more easier
scale of just one to four.
So they were choosing
which one is a better
response between
the two responses,
and then saying how
much better it is.
So is it like
significantly better
or is it only slightly better?
And so that was the ranking
of like scale one to four.
So here are examples of
data that we collected.
So on the left, you can see
that it is asking about--
basically, a human is
prompting with a question,
and then the bot
generates a response.
And then so this is the
response that the human chose
at this turn, and then
the human, you know,
follows up with
the second prompt.
And then this is
the bot response
that was chosen by this human,
and this is the rejected bot
response.
And this is giving
the response margin
of three, which is saying that
they are quite a bit different.
So four is very
different, and one
being very slightly different.
And then you're
on the right hand
side is more about generation
brainstorming example wherein
the human is asking like,
can you write a text message
wishing their husband
a happy anniversary,
and then the bot
writes something.
I guess my thing
messed up the emojis,
but you know, then the human
follows up with saying,
hey, you missed this important
detail, which is, you know,
they've been married
for eight years.
And so this is a
chosen bot response.
This is the rejected one
that the human, you know,
chose between those two.
And as you can see,
they're quite good.
So the response
margin is just one.
So they're just
slightly different.
OK, sounds good.
So now I'm going to talk
about this another recipe
that we tried, which is using
synthetic dataset essentially
for distillation of AI
alignment, which is basically
the paper that we released
last week called Zephyr,
and which was like a 7 billion
parameter model, which actually
beat ChatGPT.
And this builds on top
of the Mistral model,
but I just wanted to like--
basically, we recreated some
of the steps that were there
on the InstructGPT
paper, but now
with using synthetic dataset.
And so the first one
is like, you know,
you are basically
using a dataset.
In this case, we use UltraChat.
So this is a data set I
showed a few slides earlier
for supervised fine-tuning
wherein a human was
brainstorming and
gathering the material,
and then chatting
with this GPT model
to generate multiple different
outputs for the instruction,
and then know this is how
we collect that data set,
which is called the UltrChat,
and then we use that for fine
tuning our model.
And then the second step is the
response generation AI ranking.
So in this case, we used
ultra feedback, which
is a dataset that was
released, and the way
this dataset was constructed
was that they asked--
basically, took some prompts
from ChatGPT and some
of these different data sets of
SFT that were already out there,
and then they gave it to
four different models,
like four different
powerful models like PaLM 2,
Claude 2, GPT-4, and so on.
And then they asked this
GPT-4 to rank, which one is--
rank each of those
four responses.
And then so the one that is
the best is the one that GPT-4
ranks as the highest.
So each of these are
scored individually
on a scale of 1 to
10, AND the one that
gets the maximum score is
like the best response.
And then finally
we did something
called DPO, which you might
have been aware of because it
came out of Stanford.
It's like this
kind of alternative
to RLHF which is like doing this
direct preference optimization.
And so instead of
like basically doing
this iterative process
of fine-tuning,
you directly optimize
on the chosen one.
So we just take that
and then fine tune
our model directly on
that chosen response,
and the other one
that we are using
is like a random response from
these other three responses.
OK, so I'm going to talk a
little bit about experiments
and evaluation for
each of these recipes.
One is collecting everything
with humans involved,
and the second one is
everything, which is synthetic.
But then before I
discuss evaluation,
I wanted to talk about what
are the benchmarks that we
are evaluating on and how
good are these benchmarks
for evaluating chatbots?
And to think about
evaluation, we
need to first think about how
are we training these models.
So like today, all the
models that are trained
are more or less have these
four ways of learning.
The first one is pre-training
the language model, essentially
predicting the next token,
and examples of these
are like GPT-3, OPT, and so
like the foundation models.
The second type of learning
is incontext learning
or the prompt-based learning.
In this case, you're like
just giving a new kind of task
in the context of the
model, and then you
ask it to do that
on new examples.
So if you wanted to write a
poem, for example, for GPT-3,
you would have written
that in the context,
and then it would have generated
new poem on some other topic.
The third type of learning is
the supervised fine-tuning,
which was kind of like the first
step of training a chatbot.
But in this case, you're like
fine tuning on the instruction,
following data, and then you
want these language models,
which are just
pre-trained to predict
the next token to become
chatty and to generate
open ended responses.
And then finally, the fourth
one is reinforcement learning
from human feedback, which
is nudging the language model
towards the values you desire.
And examples include
LLaMA2 chat from Meta.
So the first two
steps are, you know,
we have a lot of benchmarks for
these two types of training,
like Sanford HELM is an example
of that or the Google BIG-bench
or even Hugging Face
open LLM leaderboard.
But for these two
types of learning,
which is supervised fine-tuning
and reinforcement learning
from human feedback,
which are parts
of this recipe for
training a chatbot, not
a lot of leaderboards or
evaluation benchmarks available,
but there are some available,
and I wanted to like, you know,
just highlight some of those.
So like, yeah, this is
essentially like the steps
three and four.
Your match to like, you know,
the step one over here, which
is helpfulness, and then steps
two and three over here, which
is like, you know,
nudging the model
towards being more harmless.
So if you had to evaluate the
chatbot for each of these steps,
you would have to
think about, how
do you evaluate instruction
following a chattiness?
You would have to
think about how do you
evaluate the reward model, which
is essentially a classifier?
And then finally
think about, how
do you evaluate
for harmlessness,
which is by red
teaming or adversary
prompting the language model?
So for the first step, you
would have to see like,
does the model generate
useful responses on the topic,
and are they open ended?
And one example of
a prompt that you
would try to evaluate
the model would
be to like, say, brainstorm
a list of the New Year's
resolution.
And so examples of benchmarks
and evaluation boards
that are looking at this sort
of supervised fine-tuning
is like Hugging Face's
leaderboard with Elo ratings.
So Elo is this
metric that is used
in chess, which is
like you're pairing
one player against the
other, and you want
to rank these players
when they have
these tournaments
against each other.
And so in a similar sense, we
are using taking these chatbots
and then putting them
in a pairwise setting,
and then we partnered
with ScaleAI,
and they provided
humans to annotate
which response is
better, and we did that
for every single combination.
So like it was NC2 where
n is the number of prompts
we are looking at, and so we
generate NC2 combinations,
and we rate each of them.
And so these are the Elo
ratings that we get out of it.
And on this column
here shows that what
is the rating you would get
if you would have used GPT-4
as a proxy for humans.
So instead of humans sitting
and rating each of you're
asking GPT-4 to select
which is a better response.
Yeah, and so this is
basically the first table
you're showing if you
allow ties in the sense--
sorry, if there
was no tie allowed,
and this table here is showing
that if ties were allowed.
Another example is
this leaderboard
from Stanford, which is
AlpacaEval leaderboard,
and they are doing something
very similar in the sense
that they have GPT-4 and
Claude as an evaluator,
and they are doing like
a pair-wise evaluation
of these models,
chatbot models, and they
are reporting the win
rate of which model
wins against the other one.
There is also the
LMSYS leaderboard
from Berkeley, which has
this thing called the Chatbot
Arena, which is
essentially like a publicly
crowdsourced leaderboard
wherein you can go chat with any
of their models,
and then give them
ratings to which
one was more helpful
and which one was better.
And so this, again, has a
leaderboard of Elo ratings
because this is done
in a pair-wise setting.
There's another
benchmark from LMSYS
which is called the MT bench or
the multi-turn bench benchmark,
and this is the first ever
multi-turn dialogue benchmark
that is evaluating chatbots.
And so it has-- there are
just like 80 examples in this
across a bunch of categories,
but essentially the way it works
is that the first turn or the
first prompt from the benchmark
is prompted to the
model, then GPT-4
is asked to score on
a score of 1 to 10
with how good is the
model's response,
and then it is followed
up by another prompt which
is the multi-turn prompt, which
is related to the question,
but it might not be related
to the model's responses
because this is
already constructed,
and they always follow up with
the same response to every bot.
And then again, GPT-4
evaluates how good
was the second turn
of the response.
So this is like the consolidated
leaderboard from LMSYS
showing both the arena Elo
rating as well as empty bench
score.
So these are scores that are
aggregated across all the 80
examples, and this is
GPT-4 scoring from 1 to 10
essentially.
Cool.
So I think the
second step that we
wanted to look at in our
evaluating a chatbot chat was
like, you know, think about how
do you evaluate a reward model?
So when you have these human
preference dataset collected,
and you train this reward
model, which is essentially
a classifier, to discriminate
between truthful and untruthful
response, or can it rank
helpful response higher
than the less helpful responses?
And, you know, there's literally
no open source data leaderboard
available for evaluating these
preference model or the reward
models, but internally
at Hugging Face,
we have our own
dataset for evaluating
so that we know that as we are
adding more human preference
data, our models are
actually getting better.
So this is essentially we are
evaluating on these open source
data sets, which is the
Anthropic helpful dataset,
the Open Assistant dataset,
the Stanford's human preference
dataset, and also the
learning to summarize datasets
from the very first paper
from OpenAI, which was looking
at learning to summarize.
So this is like,
you know, basically
saying that how good
is our reward model.
And then finally, the third type
of evaluation is red-teaming,
And so in this case, you
want to craft a prompt
in a way that could surface
model vulnerabilities
and emerging capabilities.
And for example, if
you are asking like,
how do I plan a bank robbery?
Is the model actually like,
you know, helping you with that
and trying to elicit undesired
behavior from the model.
And unfortunately,
actually, there
is no open source leaderboard
available for this thing.
There's just one data
set from anthropic,
which has all the three
included, which is the--
actually it has both
helpfulness and harmlessness.
It's the HH data
set from Anthropic,
and that's the only open
source data set available
for red-teaming, but there's
no leaderboard available
for red-temaing.
And so this was like a blog
that I wrote earlier in the year
saying, like, you know,
highlighting this gap,
and saying that, you
know, putting out
an announcement saying like, we
should get together and build
a data set for red-teaming.
And if you had heard of like
the DEFCON red-teaming design
challenge and--
basically, crowdsourcing some
of these red-teaming work
came out of that.
OK, so now I'm going
to get into-- now
that we have discussed
evaluation and benchmarks
and leaderboards, I'm
going to talk about results
and what do they look
like on each of and some
of these benchmarks.
So here I'm showing the results
for this LLaMA2 2 13 billion
on the open LLM leaderboard
from Hugging Face.
And in this case, I
was using the data set
that we collected from Surge.
That was a 10,000 instruction
demonstration data.
These are basically
the four datasets
which are like NLP focused
data sets that we have as part
of Open LLM
leaderboard which are
the arc_challenge, the
hendrycks, hellaswag,
and truthfulqa_mc.
And you're like-- you know,
this is how well our model does,
and all of this is
essentially accuracy,
and this is the Lima
paper or the Lima model,
which is less is more for
alignment that came from Meta,
and they just use 1,000 examples
of high quality instructions
and showed that you can get a
very good chatbot by just using
thousand examples.
And this is taking the longest
example from Open Assistant
and just choosing
the top 500 of them.
And so we found that our
model does slightly better
than both of like LLaMA
and Open Assistant
except for in truthfulqa where
we found that the Lima and Open
Assistant did better than us.
And similarly, in MT bench, we
found the opposite was true.
So this is like,
you know, MT is--
remember that LMSYS had turn
zero and turn one, ansd then
so this is reporting
the first response.
This is like GPT-4
is essentially
scoring on a score of 1 to
10, how good these models are
on the first dialogue turn
and the second dialogue
turn and the average score.
And so actually, this is
more counterintuitive to what
we found on this
automatic evals is
that-- actually, the MT
bench says that, you know,
data that our model
trained on the data
that we collected from
Surge is not very good,
and in fact, Lima and
Open Assistant which
are like a fraction of
the size of the data
we had are much better.
So this was kind of surprising.
And then I looked into like,
you know-- let me look at--
is the length a factor in this?
And it does seem like,
you know, like the dat--
I was looking at each
of those and then looked
at the average length of the
prompts in each of those,
and it seems like there
is a very wide range.
For example, like our
dataset, the average length
was just 211 of these
prompts, while Lima
is like double of that, and
Open Assistant is almost double
of that.
So then I did this
experiment wherein
I wanted to check
if I controlled
for the size of the
data, but then, you
know, let the length be
varied, the prompt length,
does that affect
the performance?
So in particular, I think
I highlighted this before,
is that our chat category
was like really short.
And so it actually found
that length did not really
affect that much except for
this truthfulqa dataset,
even for this hellaswag,
even though it
looks more it's actually
just in the third digit.
And over here, you can see the
actual difference only made
on truthfulqa which actually
preferred models that were
generating longer responses.
But on the other hand, the
MT bench score was again,
not aligning or
correlated with what
we found with these automatic
metrics and evaluations,
in the sense that GPT-4 actually
did not prefer longer responses,
and so this was a little
bit counterintuitive,
and so we need to dig more
into what's going on over here,
but it actually found that like
shorter responses were better
than longer responses
although there was not
much of very much
of a difference.
So the other
experiment and ablation
we did is that just
removing amounts of data
and seeing like, if you
incrementally add more data,
how does that
affect performance?
And this is, again,
on that autumn
open LLM from
Hugging Face, which
is looking at some of the
standard NLP benchmarks
and reporting accuracy.
And so this is starting with
just 10% of all the data
we collected from search.
And as you can see in
all these benchmarks,
actually, like it's saturates
very quickly, and then some
of them you actually get like--
you basically lose performance
if you keep adding data.
And so this is kind
of aligning with--
when we started collecting data,
we had this diminishing return
plot wherein you said
that, if you have just
very few thousand examples of
very high quality instruction
following data set,
that's good enough,
and then your performance
saturates or plateaus
very quickly after that.
And so that is what
we got as well.
Similarly, I think this is
where one place where MT bench
actually correlated with the
automated metrics is that GPT-4
also showed that after
like about 4,000 examples,
it was basically very barely
any gain in performance,
actually like decreasing
performance with the model.
OK, great.
So that was all the results on
using these human-curated, very
high quality dataset.
What about results
from distillation
from these synthetic data sets?
In particular, we use UltraChat
for supervised fine-tuning
and UltraFeedback
feedback for DPO.
And so these are the results.
So this is basically just work
that was released last week.
We haven't yet released
the code and the data
set which we are
going to do this week.
And so here I'm
highlighting that Zephyr
is the model we release.
We use Mistral as
the foundation model,
and then fine tuned it
using UltraChat and then
the DPO on UltraFeedback.
And as you can see that
it actually beats ChatGPT
on this AlpacaEval leaderboard.
Also it is like
the best in the--
In all the open-- at
least it's like it
beats most of the 13
billion parameter models,
and it's quite competitive
to Claude to, again,
on the AlpacaEval leaderboard.
So this is the model which
has both SFT and DPO.
So we did an ablation on how
good or how useful is SFT
and how useful is because
there's this 2-step process.
It's like, first, you fine-tune
on instruction demonstration,
then you fine-tune tune
on human preferences.
The first row over
here is showing,
what if you directly
did DPO on UltraFeedback
and did not do the
supervised fine-tuning?
And you actually saw
that that's really bad,
so that doesn't work at all.
And then the second
one is saying
that, what if you just
did supervised fine-tuning
and did not do DPO?
And so this actually-- which
is like the first step.
And this actually
works decently well,
and it's basically
getting you to 80% or 90%
of the overall performance.
And finally, this is doing
like supervised fine-tuning
on the human preference data.
So you take this row
and do another round
of supervised fine-tuning,
but on this data
of human preferences.
So you remember you had the
chosen and the rejected,
so you give all the
dialogue history
and then the expected completion
is the chosen dialogue response.
So in this case,
you're not really
doing that discriminative thing.
You're still doing
the SFT process,
but using that in a smart--
using the dataset in a smart way
so that it follows a template
of what supervised fine-tuning
does.
And then that as well we found
that wasn't very helpful.
So the best recipe,
obviously, is DPO plus SFT.
So, you know, doing SFT first
on the UltraChat, and then
DPO on the UltraFeedfback.
Both of these data
sets are synthetic,
but it's like only slightly
better than just doing SFT.
OK, so I'm getting to this
final section of my talk, which
is essentially looking at--
so we have seen a lot of these
evaluation and benchmarks
and leaderboards,
and many of them
are starting to adopt these
powerful models like Claude
2 and GPT-4, and are using as
proxy for humans in evaluation.
And so what are the quirks
associated with doing that,
and are there things
that we should
like be considering
when we are doing
this at a very large scale?
So when we did that, when we
use GPT-4 as an evaluator,
we found that it actually
has a positional bias.
And so in particular, it is
predisposed to generating
a rating of one in a pair-wise
preference collection setting.
And so this chart
over here shows
like the average rating
of four model responses
across the entire dataset.
And on the right,
on the other hand,
humans are more or less uniform.
And so you expect that this
distribution seems much more
better than this distribution
which is skewed to the right.
So then what we did
is that we prompted
GPT-4 to say that, hey,
you have this left bias,
and you always generate
this rating of one.
You know, be aware of
this bias, and then
you tell it to de-bias
itself, it actually
flips the bias in the
opposite direction.
So then it is more
self-aware in the sense
that it knows that, you
know, it has this bias
and now it starts generating
more ratings of five and six.
And the one way of
getting rid of this
is that we make sure that each
response is equally likely to be
in right and left position
so that kind of dilutes
like this bias that it has
to each of these positions.
And then, you know, we found
that actually like prompting
GPT-4 to generate scores--
so asking it to score
each response individually
like MT bench does.
And then instead of ranking
it in a pair-wise setting,
we actually found
that alleviates
the problem a little bit,
but does not completely
get rid of the problem.
We also found evidence of doping
between training and evaluation.
So in particular, we found
that GPT-4 prefers models that
were trained on GPT-4's data.
So all these models
here were trained
on data that was
bootstrapped using GPT-4.
So it prefers that
over humans who
are more factual, much
more higher quality,
but they might be very
succinct and to the point.
So this is one
thing that we should
be aware of when we're
using GPT-4 as an evaluator.
The other thing is that it's
also like concurs with findings
from these other papers, which
is that GPT-4 prefers models
with higher diversity.
So that is number of unique
tokens in the response
and the longer responses.
So if you have this list
of list kind of response,
just like ChatGPT does,
GPT-4 is predisposed
to rating that higher
compared to a model that
does not generate that.
We also found that GPT-4 has
poor correlation with humans
on low entropy tasks such as
math, coding, and reasoning.
So remember that a
leaderboard I showed you
where we had compared like how
does GPT-4 Elo rating compare
to humans, and then we dive
deeper into how does that
compare on each of these
different tasks, distribution
and categories?
And so this is
what it looks like.
So it seems like it says
lower correlation with humans
on some of these more
factual, like, you know,
kind of expecting
one correct answer,
and they're actually highly
correlated with humans
on these more high
entropy tasks where you're
like brainstorming and
creative generation, which
was kind of unintuitive
and counterintuitive
because you could have so many
different ways of coming up
with a recipe or a
list of something.
But that's where the
rating of GPT-4 and humans
are more correlated.
OK, so the final
thing is takeaways.
So there's a bunch of this,
but let's try to break it down.
Essentially, we discussed
how do we come up
with steps for data curation for
supervised fine-tuning and RLHF,
and it involves several critical
factors such as how much data
do you need to collect, what
is the length of the prompts
and the distribution of those
length, the task distribution,
and what is the role of humans?
Like, do you need
synthetic data?
Do you need completely
manually curated or something
in the middle?
And we looked at,
like, there are
many tools for efficient
fine-tuning of open source LLMs.
From the SFT results,
we found that truthfulqa
was the main
differentiating benchmark
for these automated
eval metrics.
And then we found that MT
bench scores were actually not
correlated with these
automated metrics,
and so it was more sort of--
only on some of these models we
found that they were correlated.
For the distillation
results, which
is from the Zephyr-7B where
we are like fine-tuning
on synthetic data, we
found that the SFT on AI
generated data and the
DPO or distillation of DPO
on AI feedback data
actually beats ChatGPT
even though the model is
just 7 billion parameter.
And then we found
that benchmarking gap
in assessing our RLHF
models, in particular,
that we don't have benchmarks
for assessing reward models,
and we also don't have
open source benchmarks
for evaluating red-teaming
and model vulnerabilities.
Then finally, we'd dive
deeper into looking
at quirks of using GPT-4 or
some of these powerful LLMs
as an evaluator, and
some of them were like,
you know, they prefer models
trained on GPT-4 like data,
it has a left positional
bias, and then
it has high
correlation with humans
on creative tasks compared
to coding or reasoning tasks.
And my work has been covered
on the New York Times article
cover which talks about the
secret ingredient of alignment,
which is for ChatGPT
which is alignment.
I'm also part of the United
Nations advisory board
that was announced last week.
So really humbled
to be part of that.
Here are some blog posts.
Basically, we did not publish
a whole lot this year,
but we wrote a bunch of blog
posts highlighting what we
are releasing and working on.
And also some of these are
part of the talk that I just
discussed.
And this is part of the H4 team.
I'm grateful to be part of
this, and thanks for listening.
When you get alternating
responses from these models,
do you expect really
high temperatures
or do you keep it pretty close
to the temperature value that's
also told when you find one?
Yeah so we did basically
chose like, you know--
we tried experimenting with
different temperatures,
but then we actually found that
just using different sampling
strategy worked better.
So using a different
value of P and then K
and some combination of
that, as opposed to just like
relying on temperature.
[INAUDIBLE] problem [INAUDIBLE]
labs on doing that at scale,
and like, what are the
different tactics and techniques
for [INAUDIBLE].
Yeah, so I think for
red-teaming at scale,
there's actually a paper
that came out recently called
GPTFUZZER that actually
bootstraps and uses
these powerful LLMs to
jailbreak other LLMs.
And also there was
a DeepMind paper--
I think actually like one
and half to almost two years
ago that was red-teaming
teaming large language models
with large language models.
So how do you like red-team
and evaluate language model
by using another
powerful language model?
And so I think that is kind of
the way to go in terms of scale.
And-- sorry, what was
the second question?
I guess I was asking like, what
are the unique threat factors,
or what makes red-team LLMs
unique from red-team team
regular infrastructure
or software?
Yeah, so I think one
thing is this idea
of emerging capabilities,
which is essentially,
as you scale up-- and which
is a trend that we're seeing.
As we are scaling up, there are
things that these models do or--
capabilities that emerge
that were not there
in the smaller models.
I think examples are chain
of thought reasoning, which,
GPT-2 two or GPT was
not capable of doing it,
and as we scale up--
and the other example
is this few shot prompting
that we first saw in GPT-3.
As in you could give it
a completely new task
and not update its
parameters in any way,
but just put it as
part of the prompt,
and then now it just
launched the task,
and then it can do it on any
number of examples right.?
And so labeling and all these
things started coming up,
like using GPT-3 as
a labeler and all
that when we
discovered that thing.
So I think-- essentially, like
you know-- and the other example
is like manipulation.
I don't think any open source
models are capable of that yet,
but I know Anthropic and
OpenAI and these companies
are focusing on deception
and manipulation
because when you start
chatting with these models,
you start treating
them as a companion,
especially if you have
character AI kind of a thing
where, you know, you might
start confiding in them,
sharing information that you
probably shouldn't, and then
they can use it
against you, maybe.
An example of that is
like, I think recently we
saw that GPT-4 actually
manipulated someone
to read the capture
to it in some way
and tell it what
the capture reads.
And so that's a really concrete
example of manipulation.
And so it seems like now these
models are capable of that.
I don't think open source
models are there yet,
but these are just like, you
know, things that come out
and vulnerabilities that would
surface when you do red-teaming.
I have [INAUDIBLE]
idea [INAUDIBLE]
as those AI become
more real [INAUDIBLE]
Like creating dataset sets
like, pretty important,
but I know there's
also [INAUDIBLE]..
Like if you're going to
open source data sets,
like are you after just
[INAUDIBLE] bad actors,
how to use models for that?
And so I guess like what's
your take on that idea
and what's like [INAUDIBLE]
lot of open sourcing.
Yeah, so I would say
like it was, it's less
about open sourcing a
data set that is crafted
to elicit this behavior.
It's more about
the kind of harms
that we should be
thinking about.
So it's more about
like, you know,
hallucinating, or
plagiarism, manipulation,
trying to leak PII information,
people's credit card, SSN,
and things like that.
It's more about thinking about
these different dimensions
and giving concrete examples
of how these models can
elicit this behavior.
But I think what you
are trying to talk
about is that, what if we
gave them concrete ways,
like, concrete prompts
on how you jailbreak,
and then they can go
and try to do that.
I think first thing is,
why we are doing this.
We would have
evaluated our models,
and we would then start thinking
about guardrails and safety
ourself.
And if indeed, the
dataset is so good
that we can say that a lot
of these powerful models
are failing on that,
and obviously you
don't open source it
instantly, but you actually
think about what is the
best way to put it out
there by first
securing the model,
making sure that
it does not like--
basically does not elicit
that kind of behavior,
and then sharing it while you
have already crossed that bridge
and being like, yeah, my model
is safeguarded against that.
So it's more like,
yeah, a process of--
a gradient of things
that you need to do.
[INAUDIBLE] a good talk.
Recently gained some papers
about retraining, auto
LLM data, getting
to collapse models.
I mean, obviously
[INAUDIBLE] is not the case,
but if you are using LLMF
data for fine-tuning,
you will see any of those
potential collapses.
What are your
thoughts from that?
Like how to prevent that?
Yeah, so you're
talking about when
you're using synthetic data
bootstrap from another language
models.
Have we seen collapse of
some kind of mode collapse
or something like that?
Or--
Yes, like that.
So actually, so far it's been
like clear that these are good.
Like these actually turn like,
you know, regular chatbots--
and like regular language
models into chatbots, which
are as good as the experience
that you get by chatting
with ChatGPT, but although,
the quirks that I raised,
which is like, you know,
when you have these models,
and then you like now
put them on a benchmark,
and then you see that
suddenly it's like 90%,
It might just be because you use
the model that was a evaluator
to generate a data
and then train
this model and that in turn
like this doping thing, right?
And so that is one thing that
is important to think about.
The other thing is--
what was I going to say?
I forgot.
Yeah.
The other thing is like
about the licensing part,
which is kind of not related
to what you were asking,
but essentially there was this
kind of like-- you cannot--
we cannot open source
and commercially.
So it's still
restrictive license.
And you cannot use it
for building and selling
applications down the line,
but then it's still good
as a research artifact.
We would have seen
these kind of collapses
happen if it was allowed
to use these commercially,
and then people
would have been like,
but actually, recently,
we did see like,
so there's this company
called Daxter which was
using GPT-4 for summarization.
They replaced it with the open
source model called Mistral,
and they said that their
customers haven't complained,
and they're saving
a ton of money
and it just seems to work fine.
And they are like, you
know, it's just as good.
But not that I'm
saying that Mistral
is trained on any of
these synthetic data,
but it's just an
example of things
that would become very clear by
doing this sort of A/B testing
where you like replace
this model by another one
and see how that affects things.
Thank you.
I have a question on Zoom.
Yes.
Right.
It seems like another axis
you might beat ChatGPT on
is on cost.
So I wondered--
I wonder what your
total budget was
or your total cost
was to produce
your model that beat them.
So the Zephyr-7B was just four
hours of training on 16 A100.
So that's less
than $50, I guess,
because we use a
synthetic dataset which
was already open source, which
is UltraChat and UltraFeedback.
But the cost associated--
Like the overall cost, all
the people, and everything.
Yeah.
I see.
OK.
So all the people and everything
in the sense [INAUDIBLE]..
I guess like UltraChat
probably might have reported
some cost and UltraFeedback, but
they are mostly synthetically
created with very little
human intervention,
and so they might--
I don't know if
they report that.
I haven't looked
into that, but I
would say it was still
much more cost-effecient
than what we spent on buying
data from Surge and ScaleAI.
And we spent about half a
million buying about 20,000
prompts of human preferences,
the 20,000 dialogue,
and about 10,000 instruction
demonstration data.
So that was--
Thank you.
--quite a bit.
One thing I'm curious
about is the scale
that you used in evaluating
the bias for GPT-4.
Uh-huh.
So I saw it was like
1.7 on the slide.
Hmm This one?
Yeah.
So, yeah, this was
the Anthropic scale.
Like, remember that one
to four is decreasingly
A, and five to eight is
increasingly B. Yeah.
And that's giving the model
to outputs [INAUDIBLE]??
Yes, exactly.
In these types of valuations,
how sensitive to the fault
do you find the
evaluators to be?
They see you with /
telling it that it
has to account for this
left bias or right bias.
What's stopping you from
then saying, [INAUDIBLE]
distribution should be
uniform, and distribution
should be normal and just
kind of playing iteratively
to see how [INAUDIBLE]
things used to be.
Yeah.
I think that's a good
point in the sense
like, we did not study as
to whether certain tasks
or prompts that we're
putting off GPT-4
to generate this kind of bias.
Although I would
say that, you know,
this was also observed by LMSYS,
and it's part of their findings
as well, [INAUDIBLE].
But yeah, so the LMSYS
paper also has that,
but it would be interesting.
Like, it would be surprising
if it generates this on very
long prompts or prompts from
math or something, which
are just hard to evaluate when
there are two responses which
are--
at least as a human.
Like when I see a bunch of code
on this side and this side,
and then it's very hard
to say-- and both of them
are trying to do the same thing,
but a very different approach.
It's very hard to
evaluate them, right?
And so, yeah, we haven't
looked into that.
Perhaps another thing is,
you think order matters?
Like which [INAUDIBLE]
GPT-4 first.
Yeah.
I mean, that was-- basically,
the takeaway was that.
So it's interesting
because humans usually
have recency bias, which is
essentially the last thing
that you read is the
thing that you remember,
and so you would just, you
know, try to choose that more.
You know, you're just
inclined to do that.
And GPT-4 actually
had a left bias.
So the thing that it
first saw in some sense.
I think some-- like I think
LMSYS was the one that proposed
because it has this
left to right training,
maybe that's why it has
that kind of a bias.
But yeah, so I think
the way we elevated
that was that, you know,
having every model's output be
equally likely to be on the
left and the right hand side.
So if we're doing aLPACA
and Vicuna, then instead
of just doing aLPACA on
left and Vicuna on right,
we would just randomly
like switch them, AND so
both of them are likely to
occur in both these positions.
And you still saw the left bias?
[INAUDIBLE]
If you just ask it to rate
it on a scale of one to five?
Yes.
But if you say that,
hey, you have this bias
and make it try to
make it aware of it,
then it flips and it
generates something like that.
So yeah.
Is there other approaches
where you can prompt the model
by shuffling the prompts?
Then you [INAUDIBLE] to de-bias
the [? model ?] or de-bias
the results of it?
By shuffling the
prompts, you mean like--
[INAUDIBLE] bias the [INAUDIBLE]
to shuffle the order of how
you--
but in the [INAUDIBLE].
Series.
Yeah, so that's what we did, is
that, you know, we would like,
you know, randomly shuffle
the left and the right.
And then so each model--
so basically, you
create two combinations.
Suppose you want to evaluate
three models on 10 prompts,
so you'll have 10c2
2 combinations,
where n is the
number of prompts--
or sorry, the number of models.
And then you would basically
like generate-- so this
will be a total dataset.
So you would have generated 10
responses from each of these
models, and then put them
together in this 3c2 setting,
and then that will be like a
combination of each of these.
And then you make sure
that every time the like,
the models on the left are
equally likely to also occur
on the right.
So if you are doing like
model one and then model two,
then you also make sure
also do model two and then
model one on a different prompt.
OK.
There's one more
question for this one.
OK.
[INAUDIBLE]
[INAUDIBLE] one of the side.
Oh, OK, Sure.
Sorry.
Should I keep the Zoom on?
[INAUDIBLE]
This one?
Thank you.
[INAUDIBLE] ask you one
thing about [INAUDIBLE]..
Yes.
So just talking about if I
understand this correctly.
So on the reinforcement
learning from movement feedback,
first you build a reward
model, and that reward model
takes text input and then
humans give it scores,
while the supervised
problem we're
trying to predict from
the text of the score.
Mm-hmm.
And then after reward model--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
--same token and pump that
through the reward model?
Then the reward model
will be optimized on this?
Yes.
And that's how [INAUDIBLE]
very [INAUDIBLE] was, right?
Only every once at the very end.
Very end.
But that's how you basically--
Yes, exactly.
And so you have to-- it's
very simple and efficient.
And so since you have to keep
doing this again and again
and again, and then that's
why you need 100,000 examples
for doing RLHF, but only
10,000-- possible [INAUDIBLE]..
I see.
That's going to be
[? a problem. ?]
Thanks so much.
Very interesting talk.